<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="content.xsl"?>
<page>
	<title>&lt;header&gt;</title>
	<section>
		<title>Description</title>
		<paragraph>This element defines output for the beginning of an MOTD listing.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>This element is optional and may appear only once per scheme.</paragraph>

	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Attributes</title>
		<attributes>
			<attribute name="color" required="No" evaluated="Yes" defaultvalue="normal text color" datatype="Numeric">The color to be used when the engine /echos the data.</attribute>
			<attribute name="indent" required="No" evaluated="Yes" defaultvalue="N\A" datatype="Numeric">The amount of indent the engine should use when the data is wrapped.</attribute>
			<attribute name="target" required="No" evaluated="Yes" defaultvalue="status" datatype="Mixed">The window in which the data should be displayed.  May be a window name or a keyword (see below) and multiple keywords may be used.</attribute>
			<attribute name="sound" required="No" evaluated="No" defaultvalue="N\A" datatype="Resource">The name of the resource sound file to be played when this element is triggered.</attribute>
			<attribute name="halted" required="No" evaluated="Yes" defaultvalue="false" datatype="Boolean">Whether or not the engine should halt output of this element.</attribute>
		</attributes>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Keywords</title>
		<keywords attribute="target">
			<keyword name="active">Sends output to the active window, regardless of which connection triggered the output</keyword>
			<keyword name="activechannels">Sends output to all channels on the active connection</keyword>
			<keyword name="localchannels">Sends output to all channels on the connection where the output was triggered</keyword>
			<keyword name="globalchannels">Sends output to all channels on all connections</keyword>
			<keyword name="activestatus">Sends output to the status window of the active connection</keyword>
			<keyword name="localstatus">Sends output to the status window of the connection that triggered the output</keyword>
			<keyword name="globalstatus">Sends output to all status windows</keyword>
			<keyword name="allactive">Sends output to the status window and all channels of the active connection</keyword>
			<keyword name="alllocal">Sends output to the status window and all channels on the connection that triggered the output</keyword>
			<keyword name="allglobal">Sends output to all channel and status windows</keyword>
		</keywords>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Data</title>
		<paragraph>Text, mIRC control codes and identifiers and constant keywords.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Multiple line entries are supported and will be displayed as individual lines.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>The $mts.motd() identifier may be referenced within this tag.  The arguments and returned data are listed below.</paragraph>
		<identifiers>
			<identifier name="$mts.motd(date)">Returns the date the MOTD was last modified</identifier>
			<identifier name="$mts.motd(time)">Returns the time the MOTD was last modified</identifier>
		</identifiers>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Engine Requirements</title>
		<paragraph>The engine should evaluate and display the data contained in this tag before any actual MOTD data is displayed.  Stored data should be retained until the listing is finished.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>The color, indent and target attributes should be evaluated and inserted into the /echo command in the proper place. When a keyword is used in the target attribute, the engine should process the keyword as specified (see the "Keywords" section for the target attribute).</paragraph>
		<paragraph>Multiple lines should be displayed individually, each line retaining the settings specified in the color, indent and target attributes.</paragraph>
		<paragraph>If the halted attribute is set to true, the engine should evaluate the text contained within the raw but NOT display it.</paragraph>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Examples</title>
		<example title="Declaration">
 <![CDATA[<header color="14" target="activestatus,active">[ MOTD for $server ( $+ $mts.motd(date) / $mts.motd(time) $+ ) ]</header>]]>
		</example>
	</section>
</page>